Hasan Mahmoud

2262600995 | workspace@hasanmahmoud.com | www.hasanmahmoud.com | Oak Creek, Wisconsin

PROFESSIONAL SUMMERY

Highly focused and talented Junior full stack developer with experience in a customer-oriented environment and recently achieved a bachelor's degree in Computer Science. Trained in supporting a variety of network environments, technologies, and related equipment, with the use of programing languages such as JavaScript, React.js, CSS, HTML and workflow software such as GitHub. An exceptionally sharp innovator with excellent communication, critical thinking, and customer service skills, adding immediate value to an organization.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science with a certificate in IT June 2022

University Of Windsor

SKILLS

- Strong understanding of reactive JavaScript frameworks (React.js, Node.js, Redux)
- Experience in developing User Interfaces using HTML/CSS, and bootstrap
- Understanding of the web development process, including design, development, and deployment
- Experience with version control git
- Ability to work in a collaborative multi-application team environment

WORK EXPERIENCE

WordPress Developer, Air Duct Marketing

Feb 2022 - Current

- Developed and modified mobile-friendly websites mostly built on WordPress and all the associated HTML,
 CSS, and JavaScript code
- Provided customer support, fixed websites bugs and issues, kept software up to date and fulfilled
- Uploaded websites to chosen live server and redirected desired domains towards new websites ensuring 99.9% uptime.
- Technologies and Methodologies: WordPress, Responsive Design, HTML/CSS, JavaScript

Full Stack Developer Intern, WECCC

Jan 2022 - Jun 2022

- Built frontend using functional react components using react hooks
- Implemented backend API endpoints to fetch user data
- Collaborated with 3 interns and senior developer to brainstorm and implement ideas and feedback into app's development
- Performed code reviews and participated in Agile development process
- Technologies and Methodologies: React.js, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, and Git

Web Developer, AuctionHaeus & Liquidation Center

Sept 2021 - Jan 2022

- Applied the use of React JavaScript to create mobile-friendly, fast, and responsive SPA website in a timely and effective manner, achieving 100% customer satisfaction
- Met with AHL to go over details, and discuss website needs, design, and option on some of the recommendations to create an effective website
- Tested website and performed user testing and troubleshooting before live deployment insuring 0 issues/bugs on website deployment
- Technologies and Methodologies: React.js, HTML/CSS, Heroku